So the first one here is this glaring typo in the given name column for David Gustafsson.
这里的第一个明显的打字错误出现在名字列 David Gustafsson 上
David spelled D s v i d. As you can see in the contact column here his email has David,
将 David 拼写了D s v i d 从联系方式栏可以看到 他的电子邮件中的正确拼写是 D a v i d
so this is definitely a typo.
所以该处是拼写错误
So how could this have happened?
为什么会出现这种情况呢？
This is probably just another data entry error.
这可能也是一个数据输入错误
And, why is it important to fix this?
解决这个问题为什么很重要呢？
Well, if you want to email or send mail to this person,
如果你想给这个人发邮件或电子邮件
if you misspelled their name that's not very nice for David here.
但是将他的名字拼错了
Again, that's if you're just sending email in
或者你从这个患者表中挑出这个名字
an automated fashion by picking at this name from this patient's table.
并以自动方式发送电子邮件 对 David 来说都是不礼貌的
So, time to document it.
因此要把它记录下来
These treatments and patients table are starting to pile up here.
治疗表和患者表的观察记录在这里显得很挤
So, let's separate these into sub-headers again.
所有我们把它们归到两个子标题下面
This data wrangling template can be adjusted as you see fit here.
你可以根据需要调整数据整理模板
It's not a rigid document.
记录格式不一而同
Tweak it to your own personal preferences.
根据个人喜好进行调整即可
So, the next issue is in the treatment table here.
下一个问题出现在这里的治疗表
Specifically, the auralin and novodra columns.
具体来说是 Auralin 和 Novodra 列
There are a few issues with this column but let's dial in on one right now.
可以看到此列有若干问题 但现在我们先针对其中一个进行分析
The fact that these dosages are documented in digit, digit, u form.
这些剂量的记录方式是数字、数字、u 的格式
So, for the first patient in this table,
看一下这个表中的第一个病人
the starting dose of auralin was 41 units and the ending dose was 48 units.
其 Auralin 的起始剂量为 41 单位 结束剂量为 48 单位
These should actually be in separate columns but we'll handle that later.
起始剂量和结束剂量实际上应该归在不同的列中 但这个问题我们稍后处理
The fact that there's the letter u here attached to the end means that
附在数字后门的字母 u
Pandas would not be able to interpret this variable as a float or an integer,
意味着 Pandas 无法将此变量解读为浮点数或整数
which is required for calculations.
而只有正确解读为浮点数或整数才能进行计算
Because the letter u is there Pandas would force it to the data type object.
因为有字母 u Pandas 强制将它归为对象数据类型
Which is basically a string in Pandas.
体现为字符串
That means we can't perform calculations
这样一来
using the starting and ending doses for each drug.
我们不能使用每种药物的起始和结束剂量进行计算
That's a big deal. So, how could this issue have happened?
这是一个大问题 那么为怎么会发生这种情况呢？
Sometimes it's just poor planning on behalf of whoever's recording this information,
有些时候是因为信息记录者
this clinical trial result data.
即这些临床试验结果数据的记录者计划不周全
Say if the person who was recording
比如这些信息的记录人
this information was writing it down in a piece of paper.
在纸上写下这些信息
Maybe they weren't aware that the data would be transferred from paper
而且不知道这些数据将被从纸上输入到计算机
to computer using something like optical character recognition,
比如通过光学字符识别
which would pick up these Us and dashes here,
将这里的 u 和破折号一并提取
rather than simply the integer that we want.
而不是简单保留我们想要的整数
So, let's document this now. This is a big one to fix.
因此我们需要记录一下 这是一个需要解决的大问题
And here's how the observation could be written.
我们可以这样写
All right, so backup to the treatment's table.
好 回到治疗表
One other issue is that these given names and
它的另一个问题
surnames in the treatment's table are all lowercase.
是里面的人的姓和名首字母都用的小写
Actually same goes for the adverse_reactions table.
实际上不良反应表也出现了同样的问题
This is an issue because the patients table is not lowercase.
由于患者表中人的姓名首字母不是小写 这就出现了不一致的问题
This becomes an issue if you want to join these tables later.
如果你后面要要将这些表格联接起来 缺乏统一性就成为一个问题
Which I hint for later, I think we want to.
这里我也提示一下 后面我们会联接这些表格
This is probably a data recording or data entry error issue,
这可能是一个数据记录或数据输入错误问题
and we'll document this with observations.
要将观察结果记录下来
One for the treatment's table and one for the adverse_table.
一个是治疗表的问题 一个是不良反应表的问题
And, for the final one let's scroll to the bottom of the treatment's table.
现在滚动到治疗表的底部来看最后一个问题
There are 280 rows,
一共 280 行
with last index being 279 because there's zero index to this data frame.
最后一行索引为 279 因为该 DataFrame 存在零索引
So, if you recall the size of each treatment arm was actually 175 patients in each.
我们已经知道每个治疗组实际包括 175 位患者
175 for the auralin arm and 175 for the novodra arm.
Auralin 和 Novodra 治疗组各为 175 名
So, it looks like we're missing some data here.
因此看起来该表缺少一些数据
Finding where that data lives is a separate issue.
找到数据所在的位置是另一个问题
But we'll deal with that later.
后面我们会谈到
And for now we'll just document this with an observation.
现在我们只记录这个观察结果
We should have 350 total.
我们应该有 350 名患者
175 times-
是 175 的两倍